SABITH SALEEM

SENIOR ELECTRICAL QC ENGINEER

Riyadh | +966576289786 | sabithsaleem07@gmail.com

Objective

An Electrical Engineer professional 10 years of experience 8 years of GCC experience and expertise in defining a project plan, timeline, scope, executive analysis and providing detailed recommendation based on the above (MEP). I am keenly aware of the importance of completing project on time and client satisfaction. I am accustomed to working under pressure and handling multiple tasks.

Experience

Company | SAMA JAN 2024 - Present

Project | KAFD – Saudi Space Agencies (SSA)

Responsibilities:

- Review Drawings, ITP, Method statements and Material submittals.
- Inspection and Testing Conducted detailed inspections and tests on Electrical systems to ensure compliance with quality standards.
- Quality Records Management Maintained comprehensive quality records, including inspection results, test data, and non-conformance reports.
- Material Verification Verified that materials used in installations met required standards and project specifications.
- Process Monitoring Monitored installation processes to identify potential errors and ensure adherence to quality standards.
- Coordinate with MEP contractors and Testing and Commissioning team for the schedules of Testing and Commissioning inspections of all LV and LC activities.
- Joint Inspection for all work related to Pre-Commissioning & Commissioning of Electrical work such as (Electrical, ICT, Fire alarm & light control system).
- Resolved technical inquiries, snag closeout and other issues relevant to hand over raised by Consultant and authorities.
- Report directly to Project Manager all quality issues and nonconformances for issuance of NCR/NCN and monitor the immediate closeout.

Technical Scope:

- RMU, Transformers & MV/LV switch gears,
- MV& LV Cable,
- Genset, Synch panels, PFC& ATS,
- Lighting and DALI lighting control system,
- Data Center, FTR, Data rack & Server room
- ICT System Data, WIFI, CCTV, BMS, Audio Visual, IP TV, PAVA, Intrusion system & ACS,
- Fire alarm, emergency, exit light, VESDA & DAR system,
- Earthing & Lightening protection system,
- Construct method statement for electrical activities.
- Maintaining the log sheet

Company: ARCCO | Electrical Engineer 2022-2024

Project: RED SEA PROJECT | SUDC & SUTH

Responsibilities:

• Preparation of accurate and efficient time, cost, labor and material estimation for electrical projects after the analysis of project documents and specification.

- Monitoring the electrical installation such as Package Substations, direct buried Medium/Low voltage cable for power distribution system, motor control centers, control panels, communication networks, and low current systems.
- Overseeing all project activities both on site and off site and making sure, they completed as per the client specification.
- Coordinate the day today activities at the project site according to the project schedule and project management team resolution.
- Submission of change orders and shop drawings after evaluating site conditions and other current situations to the client to compensate the project budget.
- Follow up with the site supervisors and sub-contractors to complete the project within stipulated time.
- Obtaining approvals and any required work permits.
- Raising the Request for Inspection (RFI) after execution, to project inspection department (PID) according to project specification and drawings.
- Review of work schedule, execution plan & coordinating with Project Planning Department (PPD).
- Verification and approval of quantity of work submitted by Sub-Contractor and forwarding to the project control department (PCD).
- Submission of Material Take Off to the Procurement Department.
- Daily and weekly submission of work progress report.
- Preparation of recovery plan for delayed work and review of schedule.
- Coordinate with client, consultant & main contractor for the execution of project.
- Review of design, drawings and documents.
- Preparation of technical submittals.
- Documentation for Project Closing and in house as well as client Material Reconciliation.
- Safe and timely execution of site activities as per Safety Procedures.

Company: ATC Kuwait | Electrical Engineer

2016-2021

Project: Al-Mutlaa Housing Project, Al-Zour Refinery Project, Assima Mall Project

Responsibilities:

- Planning of the project works and resources as per the signed contract/SLA/schedule/budget and standards.
- Overseeing all project activities both workshop and site making sure they are completed as per the client specification
- Coordinate the day today activities at the project site according to the project schedule and project management team resolution.

- Conduct the Load test and Preparation of technical submittals.
- Follow up with the site supervisors to complete the project within stipulated time.
- Obtaining approvals from the client for any additional work required.
- Raising the Request for Inspection (RFI) after completion.
- Submission of Materials requirement to the Procurement Department.
- Daily and weekly submission of work progress report.
- Preparation of recovery plan for delayed work and review of schedule.
- Coordinate with client & contractor for the execution of project.
- Preparation of technical submittals.
- Safe and timely execution of site activities as per Safety Procedures.

Company: SB ELECTRICALS AND CONTRACTING COMPANY (A GRADE) under BPCL REFINERY MUMBAI INDIA 2015-2016

Responsibilities:

- Make the technical compliance statement to fulfill the client requirement.
- Preparation of engineering proposal in line with project specification.
- Preparing detailed bill of materials & quantity and making indent for material purchase.
- Design for electrical panel boards as per client specifications.
- Carried out Electrical design and Electrical drawing for different projects.
- Interacting with project consultant and customer for technical clarification and approval.
- Preparation of all necessary technical documents to client in order to get approval for production.
- Coordinating with internal departments for engineering activities to execute the project smoothly & timely.
- Maintaining all necessary documents.
- Make site visits to check work updates and supervising.
- Maintaining daily, weekly and monthly reports of the site activities

Education

Cochin University of Science & Technology (CUSAT)

Major: Electrical & Electrical Engineering

2014

Accreditation

- Saudi Council of Engineers (SCE)
- Kuwait society of engineering (KSE)

Certified Training

- Electrical System Designing,
- Electric Vehicle Technology and public charging station,
- Solar grid engineer
- Environmental Health & Safety Training

Skills & abilities

- Management
- Problem solving
- Communication
- Leadership

Personal Details

Nationality: Indian

Visa Status: Transferable IqamaDriving License: KSA & Kuwait

Languages: English, Hindi, Arabic





ID. C1773161 Exp.01-Mar-23 Issued by: HADEED

ساييث سليم SABITH SALEEM کھرہائی مبانی

AL-ZUR REFINERY PROJECT

Name: Sabith Saleem

Puthalath

Winteco/Almeen Company:

Group: **EPC 055B**

Expiry Date: 26 Jun 2019

290103103721 ID:2058138 Civil ID:





جمعيّة المحندكين الكويتية KUWAIT SOCIETY OF ENGINEERS

تاريخ: 13/01/2021

رقم الشهادة :71973

شهادة الى من يهمه الأمر

تشهد جمعية المهندسين الكويتية بأن السيد / سابيث سالم - بوثالاث

ويحمل بطاقه مدنية رقم: 290103103721

الجنسية: الهند جواز سفر رقم: N3160780

تخصص رنيسي: الهندسة الكهربانية

تخصص فرعى: الهندسة الكهربانية (الالكترونية)

قد اجتاز الاختبار بتاريخ: 06/08/2018 وذلك للعمل بمهنه (مهندس)

، هذا وقد أعطيت له هذه الشهادة بناءاً على طلبه لتقديمها الى الهيئه العامه للقوى العامله

دون أدنى مسؤولية على الجمعية تجاه الغير.

علماً بأن هذه الشهادة صالحة لمدة ثلاث أشهر من تاريخ الاصدار

جمعية المهندسين الكويتية

م. فيضبل وفي خ العبتل

€ طباعه الشهاده

Town of the state of the state

رقم الإيصال:199208 تاريخ الإيصال:01/13/2021



Tel: (+965) 22445588 - 22449072 - 22420482 (+965) 22428148 P.O. Box - 4047 Safat 13041 Kuw.

www kse ora ku

@ O kseweb



Certificate of Training in Environmental Health Safety Training

This is to certify that

Sabith Saleem (Asst. Project Engineer)

Company: Al-Ameen Trade Center for Water Pump & Equipments

has completed the course on

26th August 2016 (Valid Till 26th August 2018)

Instructor V Varghese Samuel

Company Representative

Certificate No.























National Institute of Electronics and Information Technology (NIELIT) Calicut

(Autonomous Scientific Society of Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology, Government of India) http:/nielit.gov.in/calicut

Certificate of Participation

This is to certify that Mr./ Ms./Dr./ SABITH SALEEM P has participated in online program on "EV Technology and Public Charging station" organised by NIELIT CALICUT during 24th - 26th November 2021 (2hrs./day).



Coordinator

Certificate No. OLC5301

Date: 26th November 2021

Training Officer





Award of Certificate



to

NISE/012/01/...01.../2018-19/...12

SABITH SALERM. P

For successfully completing the training on

"Rooftop Solar Grid Engineer"

"NISE/012/01"

Conducted by National Skill Training Institute, Calicut, Kerala

In association with

National Institute of Solar Energy, Gurugram, Haryana

(An Autonomous Institute under Ministry of New and Renewable Energy, Govt. of India)

Supported by

[Ministry of New and Renewable Energy, Govt. of India] Date: 01-02-2019 to 12-02-2019

Director General

National Institute of Solar Energy, Gurugram

Head of Institution

National Skill Training Institute, Calicut, Kerala